（葉風・通信）
では　破るぞ　時間の檻を。→
Very well. Let us break through this prison of time.
方法は　必ずある！
There must be a way!
（左門・心の声）
≪日が　いつも東から昇るように→
Just as the sun rises in the east,
月が変わらず
満ち欠けするように→
and the moon waxes and wanes,
will victory always find the princess
世の理に守られた姫様には→
because the world's logic protects her?
どうやっても
勝ちが巡ってくるというのか？≫
（滝川吉野）≪これで
葉風さんの戻る道はつながった≫
We've established that it's possible to get Ms. Hakaze back.
≪愛花ちゃんの死は
悲劇で終わらない≫
Aika's death won't end in tragedy.
≪あとは
その方法を見つけるだけ≫
Now, we need but find the means.
Episode 11
Girl of Time
真広　声は時間を越えている→
Mahiro,
you said our voices are traveling through time, right?
さっき　そう言ってたな？
（不破真広・通信）
葉風　俺らが　その人形で→
Hakaze,
what's your theory as to how we talk through the dolls?
会話できる理屈はどうなってんだ？
（葉風）
まず　同じ形と大きさの「もの」が→
First, you need a pair of things of equivalent size and shape.
ひと組　必要だ。
同じであることによって→
Because they're the same shape,
その「もの」が
一種の共鳴を引き起こし→
they resonate with one another,
つながりが生まれる。→
and establish a connection.
（通信）板でもいいし
私のように人形でもいい。→
It could be a string, or in my case, dolls.
ただし　形が複雑である方が→
The more complicated the shape, the better the possible link.
つながりやすくもある。
それだけですか？
Is that all?
No.
いや　その「もの」には→
The items must be imbued with a portion of the spell caster's body.
術者の体の一部を
埋め込まねばならん。
魔法使いの肉体の一部が
入ることによって→
These items can only act as avatars or speak for the mage
once some part of the mage's body is added to them.
それは
いわば　術者の分身となって→
声を発する。　更に→
Also,
（通信）術者の部分が
多く含まれているほど→
the larger the body part, the stronger the connection.
つながりは強くなるのだ。
そして　この２つの人形には→
Along those lines, these dolls have a fair amount of my blood soaked into them.
私の血液が
大量に染み込ませてあるぞ。
その発想でいくなら→
Following that thought,
if we find two unusual, but similar, objects
十分に複雑で同じ形のものが
ここと向こうの島にあって→
here and on that island...
その両方に　葉風さんの体の一部が
埋め込まれていれば…。
And if both contain part of Ms. Hakaze...
We could transport her body here.
肉体も　時間を越えさせられる。
ここまでの理屈が正しけりゃ
そうなるよな。
If our theory is correct so far, that's what would happen.
Don't compare a full body with a voice.
声と体を一緒にするな。
電話と物質転送機は違う…　いや→
Transmitting one's own voice is completely different from transferring materials.
Then again,
within the rules of magic, it may be possible.
（通信）魔法論理的には可能か？→
応用できるものがあるかもしれん。
Perhaps we can apply it to something.
あるぜ。
（葉風・通信）何？
There is something.
What?
まったく同じ形をした
お前の体の一部が→
There's a part of your body that's exactly the same shape,
こっちと　そっちに　あるんだよ。
and currently exists in both places.
お前の全身骨格が！
Your full skeleton!
≪そうだ≫
That's right.
≪その骨が　時間の檻を破る鍵≫
That is the key to breaking the prison of time.
≪姫様が勝つための鍵だ！≫
The key that will ensure the princess's victory.
ボゥン　ボゥン　ボゥン！
ドカドカドカドカ！
すばらしい活躍でした
おねえさん。
That was quite a performance, ma'am.
You can leave the rest to me.
あとは　僕に任せて
飲み物でも　どうぞ。
Here, have a drink.
あなたも魔法使い？
Are you a mage, too?
いえ　あいにく
その才能はなくて→
No...
Unfortunately, I lack that talent.
留年を重ねてる大学生です。
ただし→
I'm just a college student, who's failing his classes.
I am, however,
魔法使いの足止めは得意ですよ。
（夏村）潤一郎殿…。
an expert at stalling mages.
Mr. Junichiro
世界の存亡が
懸かっているのですよ？
the fate of the world is at stake here.
You are supposed to be neutral.
中立のあなたが
何故　我らの邪魔を…。
Why would you interfere?
ふっ　決まっている。→
That should be obvious.
あのおねえさんの乳が→
Because that lady's boobs
いい感じに揺れていたからだ！
were bouncing all over the place!
How can you call yourself a man if you won't help someone like that?
そんな人を助けないなんて→
男じゃないだろう！　違うかい!?
Am I wrong?
違います。
You are.
Oh, well.
そうか
まあ　理由はいいじゃないか。
Anyway, the reason's unimportant.
気に入らなければ
実力で変えてみたまえ。
If you dislike the situation, use your strength to change it.
They say if a master attacks you with their specialty,
（潤一郎）その道の達人に
技をかけられれば→
you'll be defeated before you even know what happened.
何をされたか分からないうちに
倒されるといいます。→
魔法使い相手でも同じことですよ。
That goes for mages, as well.
≪左門殿によれば
潤一郎殿は達人≫
According to Mr. Samon, Mr. Junichiro is a master.
≪前に立たれたら
その体力が尽きるまで→
If we were to face him,
he would merely toy with us until we ran out of energy.
転がされ続けると≫
≪ならば　有効な対処法は一つ≫
Then...
There is but one valid course...
Tactical retreat!
≪戦術的撤退だ！≫
させないって。
（夏村）うっ！
Not happening!
こうなれば　当分→
If this keeps up, you'll be too dizzy to stay on your feet for long.
君が　まともに
立っていられるときはない。
≪何がなんだか分からないけど→
I don't really know what's happening,
風は　こちらに吹いてるみたいね≫
but it looks like things are now going my way.
That's right!
（葉風）
そうか！　私自身の体なのだ。
That is my own body.
Despite the difference in time,
時間がずれているゆえに
私の体内と　そちらの両方に→
my skeleton exists within me and with you.
（通信）私の骨が存在する。→
共鳴　接続する物体として
これほど強力なものはない。
There is nothing that could create a greater resonance.
But, Mahiro,
だが　真広
タイムパラドックスはどうする？
what about the time paradox?
This really is Ms. Hakaze's skeleton.
確かに　これは　葉風さんの骨だ。
でも　葉風さんが時を越えて→
So if she were to travel through time to return here,
（通信）ここに戻れば
葉風さんは　島で骨にならない。
her body wouldn't become a skeleton on the island.
なら　左門は
骨を回収できないから→
In which case Samon would be unable to retrieve the bones,
ここに骨はないはず。
and they wouldn't be right here.
でも　骨はある。
But the skeleton is here.
ないはずのものがある。
この矛盾をどうする？
What shouldn't exist, does.
What will we do about that?
だったら
骨だけ残して　時間を越える→
Then what if
she just leaves her bones to come back here?
なんてのはどうだ？
えっ？
Huh?
葉風
お前の骨は　こっちにあるんだ。
Hakaze, your bones are over here.
そっちに　骨だけ残し→
Could you transfer
the rest of your physical body on top of that skeleton?
それ以外の肉の部分を
こちらの骨に移し替える→
（通信）ってな発想で
なんとかならないか？
Would that work?
≪骨を残し　肉を移し替える？≫
Leave my skeleton here,
and transfer the rest?
If you move the rest through time,
the bones will remain on the island.
肉だけが時間を越えれば
骨は　ちゃんと　島に残る。
Samon will then retrieve those bones, and hang them here.
左門は　その骨を回収して
ここに吊るした。
どこかに矛盾が出るか？
うっ…。
Any inconsistencies?
So use the skeletons to resonate,
骨を共鳴させ
肉だけ　時間を越えさせて→
send the rest of the body through time, and reconstitute it on the one here.
こちらの骨の上で再構成させる…。
それなら
パラドックスは起こらないし→
It will not cause a paradox.
骨を通信具と考えれば
声を肉にしただけで→
If you think of the skeletons as communication devices,
it's pretty close to your communication theory— just with your flesh instead of our voice.
（通信）会話できる理屈とも近い。
いける。
We can do it.
法と術は　しかと見えておらんが
おそらく　いける！
I don't have the exact spell, but it is possible.
（葉風）だが…。
（通信）えっ？
However,
to use a powerful spell to move through time
（葉風）
時間を越えるほどの魔法ならば→
供物として　相当なレベルの
文明の産物が必要だ。→
would require a significant offering from modern civilization.
この島では
そんな供物は手に入らんぞ。
I cannot get anything like that here.
供物ですか？　それなら　たぶん…。
An offering?
For that, you could...
（左門）少年たちよ。
ん？
Young men.
いま少し…→
Just for a moment...
いま少し
話を聞いてもらえまいか？
Just for a moment, would you hear me out?
ボゥン！
ドシューー！
（宇津井）
押せ！　迷わず　押し続けろ！
Keep pushing!
Keep pushing, and don't hold back!
バシューー！
あの壁の限界は近い！
We've almost destroyed the barrier!
（男たち）戻れ　戻れ…。
Return! Return! Return! Return! Return! Return! Return!
（部下）結界第１層　臨界！
第２層に振動発生！
The first barrier has fallen,
and the second is unstable!
（哲馬）今は無視しろ！
復活の儀式を重ねる！
Ignore that for now.
We must hasten the revival ritual.
（部下）報告　急げ！
Hurry and report!
Another fruit?
（早河）また果実が!?
（部下）衛星で確認。→
Confirming via satellite.
高速で
富士山麓へ向かっています！
Heading toward Mt. Fuji, at high speed.
ドカーン！
ドカン！
（宇津井）
なっ　なんだ!?　何が起こって…。
Wh-What...
What's going on?
ガタン！
ん？
ドカーーン！
The method you devised for time travel
（左門）お前たちが導き出した
時間を越える方法…。
is absolutely correct.
（左門）完全な正解だ。
In addition, to account for the possibility of failure in our attempt to revive the Tree of Exodus,
加えて言うなら　もし我らが
復活の儀式に失敗した際には→
the barrel has been soaked with my blood
早急に　姫様と連絡がつくよう→
so that the princess could be contacted immediately.
その樽の一部に
私の血液を染み込ませ→
通信具となるようにもしてある。→
（通信）よって　時間を越える
魔法のために必要な供物は→
An offering sufficient for time travel was hidden in advance
島の中に
あらかじめ隠してあるのだ。
somewhere on the island.
≪読みどおりだ≫
Just as I thought.
I expected nothing less from the meticulous Samon.
≪堅実が信条の
左門ならでは…　だな≫
When I went to retrieve the bones,
（左門）
その供物が使用されたかどうか→
I didn't have the time to check if the offering had been used.
骨と樽を回収に行った際
確かめる時間はなかった。
まるで
大きな力に妨げられるがごとく→
As though hindered by some great power,
折あしく　海が荒れてな。
we were suddenly beset by a storm at sea.
はっ…。
（左門）少年→
Young men,
出来すぎとは思わぬか？
姫様が勝つよう→
don't you feel it's too easy?
Doesn't it feel as though
何もかもが　はじまりの樹に
運命を握られているとは感じぬか。
the Tree of Genesis is determining all this, to favor the princess?
Oh, give it up.
よせよ
何言っても　負け惜しみだろ。
You just sound like a sore loser.
However, young man,
だが　少年　お前もまた→
you're one whose fate has been twisted, as well.
運命をねじ曲げられた
一人であろう。
（左門）お前は　復讐のために
ここに来たのだったな。
You came here for revenge, did you not?
だが　都合よく　お前や
お前の友人のような特異な者が→
But do you really believe that it is a coincidence that you and your friend
姫様に手を貸す状況になったのを
偶然と言えるものか？→
ended up here, trying to help the princess?
偶然ではない！
It is no coincidence!
はじまりの樹の企みだ！
This is part of the Tree of Genesis's plot!
It manipulated logic and killed your sister,
お前が
姫様に手を貸す状態になるよう→
理を　操作して
お前の妹を殺したのだ！
all to put you in a situation where you would aid the princess.
（左門）お前の妹が死んだのは→
Wasn't your sister killed
姫様が
島に放置されたあとであろう。
after the princess was stranded on the island?
ならば　少年
お前が本当に復讐すべきは→
Then, young man,
the one you should exact revenge upon
妹を直接　殺した犯人ではない。
is not the one who killed your sister.
そのように運命を操り
理を仕組んだ→
Should you not avenge yourself on that which manipulated logic for this,
はじまりの樹ではないのか？
the Tree of Genesis?
≪はじまりの樹が→
If it killed Mahiro's sister for my sake...
私のために
真広の妹を殺したとするなら…≫
お前が　姫様に味方するのは→
Is it really your heart's desire
to help the princess?
お前の心に　かなっているのか？
Now, young man, do think about it.
さあ　少年よ　いかに考える。
≪僕も前に感じた…
愛花ちゃんの死は→
I suspected it too.
That Aika's death
葉風さんにとって
都合がよすぎると≫
was too convenient for Ms. Hakaze.
I had also considered this.
（葉風）
≪私も感じた…　真広の妹は→
It was as though Mahiro's sister were killed for my sake.
私のために殺されたようだと≫
≪葉風さんが　島に流される前に
愛花ちゃんは死んだはずだから→
I wanted to believe that Aika's death was unconnected,
因果関係はない→
because she died before Ms. Hakaze ended up on the island.
そう思い込もうとしていた≫
But time was two years out of sync.
≪だけど　時間は
２年もずれていたんだ≫
≪私が流されたあとに
真広の妹は殺されていた≫
Mahiro's sister was actually killed after I arrived here.
≪これでは　はじまりの樹が→
At this point, I cannot deny that the Tree of Genesis may have done it for my sake...
私のために仕組んだと言われても
否定できん≫
That I may be the reason Mahiro's sister died.
≪私が
真広の妹の死の原因だと…≫
（左門）少年　真に倒すべきは
はじまりの樹だ。→
Young man,
the Tree of Genesis is your true enemy.
その理不尽な意志を砕かずして
お前の復讐は終わらん。→
Your mission of revenge cannot end
until we break its unjust will.
その支配があるかぎり
我らは　樹の奴隷にすぎんのだ！
As long as it rules over us, we are mere slaves to that Tree.
Young man,
少年　我らと共にあれ。
fight with us.
理を我らの手に戻し
本当の意味で→
Return logic to our hands,
and truly save this world.
世界を救うのだ！
（潤一郎）事実上　軍は壊滅かな。
Looks like this may be the end of the army.
おねえさん
すぐまた仕掛ける準備が→
Ma'am, will the army be able to mount another attack soon?
軍にはありますか？
今回だけで
どれだけ無理したと思う？
Do you realize how difficult this offensive already was?
じゃあ　君の任務も
終わりということだ。
That would mean your mission is over, too.
Why not stop this senseless fighting and rest?
お互い　無駄な争いはやめて
休もうか。
It was senseless from the start.
最初から
無駄な争いではありませんか。
≪世界の行方は　あの二人の少年に
託されたってことか？≫
The world's fate
now rests with those two boys.
（左門）さあ　少年よ。　我らと共に→
Now, young man, join us.
Come!
さあ！
真広　よく考えろ！
Mahiro, think this through!
If Samon and the others hadn't put Ms. Hakaze on the island,
最初に　左門たちが
葉風さんを島流しにしなければ→
there wouldn't have been any reason to kill Aika.
愛花ちゃんを死なせる理は
仕組まれなかったはずだ！
Wouldn't it mean that Aika's death was caused by the actions of Samon and the others?
だったら　死の原因を作ったのは→
左門たちということに
ならないか!?
絶園の樹復活のために→
Wouldn't it mean that
Aika was sacrificed to revive the Tree of Exodus?
愛花ちゃんは　犠牲にされただけ
なんじゃないのか!?
But the Tree of Exodus—
だが
この世のために　絶園の樹は…。
Don't forget!
それに　愛花ちゃんを殺したのは
一族の誰かだ！
Aika's killer is someone from the clan!
Given all that, I can't justify taking Samon's side!
（通信）それを考えたって
左門たちにつくのが→
正しいとは思えない！
≪吉野…　その言い分は
正しいかもしれんが→
Yoshino...
That may well be true,
but I don't feel any less responsible.
私の責任が消えるとも思えん≫
≪なんの意図があって…
そうか！≫
What is he trying to...
I see!
≪僕の言葉で
今の真広が　迷うかは怪しい≫
I don't know if Mahiro will be swayed by my words.
≪でも　少しでも迷えば→
But if he hesitates long enough,
葉風さんが
供物を見つける時間が稼げる≫
I can buy time for Ms. Hakaze to find the offering.
≪左門は　この島に
時間を越えられるだけの→
Samon said he hid an offering sufficient for a time travel spell.
供物を隠したと言った≫
≪また　緊急の場合
私を呼び戻す気であったとも≫
He also said he intended to retrieve me in the event of an emergency.
≪なら　分かりづらい場所に
隠すはずがない≫
Then he wouldn't have hidden it somewhere difficult to find.
≪広くない島だ≫
This island isn't that big.
I should be able to find it.
≪自分で見つけるのも
不可能ではない≫
吉野　感謝する。
Yoshino, thank you.
Thanking you will be my lifelong duty.
貴様には
生涯をかけて感謝しよう。
≪愛花ちゃんが死んだのが→
If Aika really did die because of Ms. Hakaze...
もし　葉風さんのせいだとしても
でも…≫
But still...
Even so,
（愛花・回想）((それでも→
Everything happens for a reason.
すべてのことには訳があります))
((これも　いつかは
美しい結末の伏線になるでしょう))
Someday, this will also have a very beautiful outcome.
≪葉風さんを見捨てるのは
間違ってる≫
It would be wrong to abandon Ms. Hakaze.
≪愛花ちゃんのために
ならない気がするんだ≫
I doubt that would benefit Aika at all.
（葉風）悩むのは　あとだ。→
We can contemplate all of this later!
真広
貴様には　いくらでも謝罪する。→
Mahiro,
I will beg your forgiveness as much as you wish.
償いもする。　だが→
I will atone for everything.
But if I'm trapped in the past, I can't atone for anything!
この過去にいては
何も償うことはできん！
That is why I will return...
だから私は　そちらに戻る→
なんとしてでも！
No matter what it takes.
≪必ず供物を見つける≫
I will find the offering, no matter what!
It is logical that I should find it.
≪見つけられるのが　私の理だ！≫
（左門）少年　それならば→
Young man!
By that logic, it is also too coincidental that someone in the clan killed your sister.
鎖部の者が犯人というのも
出来すぎだ。
それも　我らを敵対させるため→
It's as though it were simply a reason to cause conflict.
こずるく
仕組まれたようではないか。→
そもそも
一族の者が殺人を犯すのは→
Not to mention, the risk is too great
リスクが大きすぎるのだ。
for one in our clan to kill.
（山本）ごほごほっ　ごほっ。
ははっ…
折れたあばらが肺に刺さったかな？
Apparently one of my broken ribs punctured a lung.
治してあげなよ。
Heal her.
失礼。→
Pardon me.
Tree within the tree,
樹の中の樹　大樹の中の大樹…。
great tree within the great tree...
うそ…　痛みが…。
No way.
The pain...
致命傷や病気は
難しいですけど。
Mortal wounds and illness wouldn't be so simple, but...
Um...
その…。
礼をする必要はありませんよ→
No need to thank him.
If you died, he's the one who'd be in trouble.
死なれたら困るのは
彼の方ですから。
（夏村）潤一郎殿！
Mr. Junichiro!
（潤一郎）はじまりの樹に仕える
鎖部の一族には→
The Kusaribe clan members who serve the Tree of Genesis
理を　みだりに犯す行為は
禁じられています。→
cannot do anything that goes against reason.
And committing murder is the biggest sin.
中でも　殺人は最大の禁忌。
もし　直接　その手で人を殺せば→
If one killed another by their own hand,
they would no longer be capable of using magic.
反動として
魔法が使えなくなるんです→
はじまりの樹に
許しを請う儀式を行うまでは。→
At least, not without a ritual to ask the Tree of Genesis's forgiveness.
儀式を行ったかどうかは→
A high clan official
could determine if the ritual had been performed or not.
一族で　高い地位にある者が
調べれば　すぐ分かります。→
So even if the Tree of Genesis forgave the act,
そして　たとえ　はじまりの樹に
許されたあとでも→
よほどの理由がないかぎり→
had the act been done without a valid reason,
一族内で
厳罰に処されることになる。→
the clan would severely punish the killer.
魔法を悪用させないためにも
絶対そうします。
It's necessary to discourage magic from being used for evil.
結界は守り通したが
人も死にすぎた。
We managed to protect the barrier.
But too many died.
樹による結果は
我らに反動がないとはいえ→
We may be unaffected by deaths caused by the Tree's actions,
but it's nothing to celebrate, either.
喜ぶことでもない。
（部下）哲馬殿→
Mr. Tetsuma...
１年前に　一族で
殺人を犯した者の調査ですが…。
Regarding the investigation into a murder by one in the clan, a year ago...
終わったか。
Is it finished?
それで　犯人は？
So who is it?
（左門）我ら一族は
魔法の力を　みだりに使えぬよう→
We are bound strongly by both the Tree and our clan laws,
樹の力と掟に　強く縛られている。
so that no one abuses magic.
それゆえ　鎖部の者が
人を殺めるなどありえん。
Thus, it's inconceivable that a Kusaribe would kill!
（葉風）それでも　鎖部の者が
犯人なのは間違いない。→
Even so,
the killer is, without doubt, of the Kusaribe clan .
Although I investigated it myself,
no one was caught in the web of magic.
私が探査しても　魔法の網に
何者も　かからなかったのだ。
What do you mean?
（通信）どういうことです？
例外が一つだけあるのだ。
There is only one exception.
If the Tree of Genesis forgave the murder,
はじまりの樹に
その罪を許された者ならば→
人を殺しても　網にはかからん。
the culprit would not be caught by the web.
You mean someone forgiven by the Tree after the ritual?
つまり
儀式を行って許された者ですか？
Yes, the web would not catch them
（葉風）そう。　許され　すでに
理を正されたゆえ　網にかからん。
because their actions would already be forgiven and deemed reasonable.
And only the Kusaribe enjoy that privilege.
そして
その特権を持つのは鎖部の者だけ。
Since no one was caught by the web,
魔法の網にかからないからこそ
犯人は　鎖部の者と→
there is no doubt that the killer is of the Kusaribe.
（通信）断定できるのだ。
犯人がいるなら
定期の調査によって→
If the killer were in the clan, they would have already been found and severely punished.
必ず　あぶり出し　罰していた…
常ならばな。
Under normal circumstances, that is.
However, in this past year,
だが　この一年ばかり
絶園の樹復活に専念し→
we have concentrated on reviving the Tree of Exodus and...
おろそかに…。
見ろ！　何もかもが
お前たちに都合よすぎる！
Once more!
Things are far too much in your favor!
姫様を利している！→
They favor the princess!
生も死も　すべて
はじまりの樹の思うがままだ！
The Tree of Genesis
completely controls life and death.
少年　そこから
自由になろうとは思わんか!?
Young man!
Would you not like to be free of that control?
≪左門は　供物をどこへ隠した？≫
Where did Samon hide the offering?
≪見つかる…　見つかるはずだ≫
I will find it... without fail!
≪私が望むかぎり
見つからないわけがない≫
So long as I wish to, there is no reason I cannot.
≪真広　軽はずみな行動はするな≫
Mahiro,
don't do anything rash.
Think about it...
≪いま少し…　いま少し考えよ→
Think things through.
Think about what is right!
何が正しいかを≫
((ゴロゴロゴロゴロ…（雷鳴）))
（愛花）((気付いてたら
閉めたらどうです？))
If you knew it was open, why didn't you shut it?
I hear a typhoon is heading this way.
((台風が
近づいているそうですよ))
((機嫌が悪いですね))
You're certainly in a bad mood.
((吉野さんと
ケンカでもしましたか？))
Did you fight with Yoshino?
（愛花）((図星のようですね))
((あいつが悪いんだ))
Looks like I guessed it right.
It's his fault.
((理屈に合わねぇことばかり
言いやがって))
He keeps saying illogical stuff.
（愛花）((理屈に合わないことが→
The fact that it's illogical doesn't make it wrong.
すべて間違っているとも
言えませんよ))
((吉野さんは
あれで問題ある人ですけど→
Yoshino does have his issues,
大抵の場合
正しいんじゃありません？))
but I believe he's usually right.
Anyway, some things in this world are simply unforgivable.
((なんにしたって　世の中には
許せねぇこともあるんだよ))
（愛花）((「お互いの思い出に→
"Let us not burden our remembrance
過ぎ去った悲しみの重荷を
負わせるのはよしましょう」))
((許しても許さなくても→
with a heaviness that's gone."
過ぎたことで　何か変わるわけでも
ないのでしょう？))
((それ
「ハムレット」のじゃねぇな))
That's not from Hamlet.
I don't recognize it.
((覚えがねぇ))
((嵐))
((ん？))
A storm...
It's from The Tempest.
（哲馬・通信）左門殿→
Mr. Samon.
１年前に殺人を犯した者の調査が
終わりました。
We've concluded the investigation into the murder a year ago by one in the clan.
そうか！　犯人が特定できたか！
I see.
So you've found the murderer!
Crap.
≪しまった！≫
吉野　時間稼ぎを狙ってたのは
お前だけじゃない。
Yoshino, you weren't the only one trying to buy time.
この報告が来るまで
少しでも　俺たちを動揺させ→
He was trying to stall us and block Hakaze's actions
葉風の動きを
妨害しようとしてたんだよ。
until the investigation results came in.
もちろん　俺が説得に応じれば
それでもよかったろう。
Naturally,
it wouldn't have hurt if his argument had persuaded me to his side.
だが　犯人を特定して
連れてきても→
But if he managed to find the killer and bring him here,
he wouldn't need to convince me not to side with Hakaze.
俺らが
葉風に味方する理由をなくせる。
Considering that was the deal.
そういう約束だったからな。
He figured that if he could divide us,
he could slow Hakaze's path to victory,
俺らを切断できれば
葉風の勝つ流れを遅らせられる。
その間に　絶園の樹復活に
こぎ着けようって→
and use that time to concentrate on reviving the Tree of Exodus.
この土壇場　計算してたのさ。
≪この少年　感情を乱すどころか→
This boy...
Not only did he show no emotion,
冷静に
そこまで　頭を回していたのか？≫
but he figured it all out alone.
Samon,
左門
お前の言うことは　もっともだ。
what you say has merit.
It would be illogical for me to ignore
なんで　鎖部のヤツに
愛花が殺されたか→
そいつを無視するのは
合理的じゃねぇよな。
why someone from the Kusaribe clan killed Aika, right?
犯人が分かったんだ。
早く連れてこさせろよ。
You know the killer's identity.
Hurry up and bring the killer here.
はじまりの樹まで
ぶっ倒す必然があるかどうか→
Let's find out if I have a reason to blow away
the Tree of Genesis, as well.
そいつの話を聞こうじゃねぇか！
哲馬　至急だ
犯人を連れてきてくれ。
Tetsuma, I need you to bring the killer immediately.
（哲馬・通信）いえ　それが左門殿…。
うん？
Impossible.
Mr. Samon,
（哲馬・通信）一族内に→
there is no one of the clan
理を　犯した者はいません。
（左門）何ぃ!?
who has gone against logic.
What?
（哲馬・通信）
犯人は　一族にいないのです！
The killer is not in the clan!
（左門）そんなバカな！
That's impossible!
（哲馬・通信）何度も確認しました！
間違いありません。
We have confirmed it.
There is no doubt.
（左門）バ…　バカな！
どういうことだ　葉風！
Impossible!
What the hell is going on, Hakaze?!
そんなはずはない！
たとえ　犯人が死んでいても→
That's not possible!
Even if the killer were dead,
はじまりの樹に
許された者以外は…。
he'd have to be among those the Tree of Genesis has forgiven...
まさか…。
It couldn't be...
ここにおいて
身内をかばいはせん！→
I have no reason to cover for my clan now!
You should know that!
分かるであろう！
バカ言ってんじゃねぇぞ。
You've gotta be kidding me.
If the killer can't be found by magic,
魔法で
犯人が特定できねぇんなら→
why the hell did I come this far?
俺は
なんのために　ここまで来た!?
理屈に合わねぇ！
It's absurd!
This is screwed up! Don't mess with me!
おかしいだろ！
ふざけんじゃねぇぞ！
Is it possible that someone else could escape the web of magic?
魔法の網にかからない犯人が
ほかにいるとでも？
（葉風・通信）いるかもしれん。
えっ？
Perhaps...
Huh?
いるかもしれんのだ…　ただ一人→
There may be
one person who could have escaped the web of magic!
魔法の網にかからぬ者が！→
（通信）はじまりの樹に従わぬ者
理を　犯しても罪にならぬ者…。
Someone who does not serve the Tree of Genesis,
someone whose illogical actions would not be considered a sin...
（葉風）いや　破壊こそが理の者が！
No, someone whose logic is destruction itself.
What the hell does that mean?
なんだよ　それは！　適当なこと…。
（葉風・通信）私が！
Stop making sh—
Just...
Just as I am the princess of the Tree of Genesis,
私が　はじまりの樹の
姫宮であるように→
a princess blessed by the logic of destruction
破壊の理に祝福された御子が→
could have been born as the Tree of Exodus's revival grew near.
絶園の樹の復活を感じて→
一人
生まれていたかもしれんのだ。
No...
いわば　絶園の魔法使いが！
The mage of Exodus!
The mage of Exodus?
絶園の魔法使い？
kimi to miteta nagareboshi oikakete
Chasing the shooting star that we saw together
Reaching this place all alone
hitori bocchi konna toko made kiteta
Hiding the feelings I wanted to express to you
kinou kimi ni ienakatta kimochi o
kotoba no naka kakusu no
within words
tooku hanarete itemo douka todokimasu you ni
No matter how far we are separated,
please let it reach you
kono michi no saki ni matsu unmei nante
The fate waiting for us down this road
is not yet known
ima wa mada
dare mo mada
shiranai kedo
by anyone
To the future drawn by numbed fingers
kajikan da yubisaki de egaita mirai he
With you we can make it
kimi to nara ikerutte
nee sonna ki ga shiteta nda
That's what I feel
kitto
with certainty
I am Kusaribe Hakaze,
the Princess of Genesis.
Everything's been turned on its head.
This doesn't feel real...
I've traveled two years through time to return.
Why are you naked, Ms. Hakaze?
The world is out of joint...
Yoshino!
（葉風）我が名は　鎖部葉風。→
Mahiro!
Is this the logic of the Tree of Genesis?
はじまりの姫宮。→
２年の時を越え　帰って来たぞ。
Episode 12
Absent Thee
from Felicity Awhile